

Personal details



Alvin Richard Calma



alvin.l.calma.ac@gmail.com



09498805361



CALOOCAN CITY

Skills

SQL

Javascript

ReactJS

HTML/CSS

People Management

Service Management

Application Support

Salesforce

JIRA

Zuora

GitHub

RPA(UIPath)

Alvin Richard Calma

Has over 10 years experience in IT industry. Primarily experienced in People Management, Production/Application Support, Incident/Service Management, and Solutions Architect. Has delved into Web Development as a freelancer using ReactJS, HTML/CSS and provided services in automations, continuous improvements and IT solutions.

Employment

Associate Manager

May 2021 - Present

Accenture Inc

- Manages a team that handles incident and problem tickets through ServiceNow to ensure that every priority item is being handled
- Performs Application (Zuora SAAS) Development and Enhancements based on client feedbacks and requirements
- Performs regular discussions to individual members of the team regarding their quarterly and annual goal/targets, objectives, actual and target deliverables

Web Developer

Dec 2020 - May 2021

C&C Technology Solutions

- Develop new user-facing features
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability
- Collaborate with other team members and stakeholders

Service Management Lead

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Asticom Technology Inc

- Leads the Asticom's IT Service Desk Team
- Leads process enhancements of ticketing system, tracking, and managing assets
- Trains service desk resources in JIRA process flows, ticket handling, customer/client support
- Performs RCA for escalated incidents

Solutions Architect

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

Asticom Technology Inc

- Develops Solutions based on client/company's requirements and pain points
- Creates, Enhances, and maintains JIRA Platform for clients and user requirements
- Technologies and platforms used JIRA Workflow, RPA (UIPath), ITSM/Service Desk

Web Developer

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

Upwork

 Performs code changes and enhancements on the application based on the client requirements

Application Support Lead

Dec 2016 - Mar 2019

Accenture Inc

- Leads a team that handles incident and problem tickets through ServiceNow to ensure that every priority item is being handled
- Ensures service delivered to our customers, meets contractual Key

Performance Indicator ('KPIs') and financial expectations.

- Designs and manages code changes based from client requirements
- Collaborates with internal customers to elicit their business concerns and translate them into system development requirements
- POC for both Project Clients and Service Managers while also reporting updates to Immediate Supervisor or Manager
- Reviews team defect fixes and enhancements making sure it corresponds to the functional and technical designs
- Finds ways to further improve the application (i.e. deploying automations, application performance enhancements, user interface improvements, ETC)
- Performs regular discussions to individual members of the team regarding their quarterly and annual goal/targets, objectives, actual and target deliverables

Senior Software Engineer

Dec 2014 - Nov 2016

Accenture Inc

- Seeks continuous improvements for the application performance, data integrity, client satisfaction
- Works on backlog incidents/defect fixes that requires deep knowledge of the application and technology
- Performs code changes to resolve production issues
- Guides the new joiners or junior software engineers with their daily tasks
- Leads an ad hoc team that are tasked to work on specifically for client incident tickets

Software Engineer

Jul 2010 - Nov 2014

Accenture Inc

- Performs code changes depending on technical designs based from client requests
- Monitors the application, GUI and batch jobs making sure that they are available and running
- Pulls up data needed for analysis (i.e. number of incident tickets per week, no. of contract with issues, ETC)
- Participates in production deployment to monitor and validate changes.

Education

BSECE Jun 2003 - Oct 2009

Technological University of the Philippines